MATT JONES

m.r.jones@live.co.uk \primattjones.wales \primattle LinkedIn

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer with 6 years of experience who feels comfortable touching all areas of the tech stack. Technical experience includes extensive work with React and spring boot based RESTFul microservices. A strong believer in XP practices with an emphasis on collaboration and feedback. Experience with mentoring junior developers.

SKILLS

Frontend Typescript, React, Tailwindess, Less, NextJS, Cypress, Jest,

Svelte/SvelteKit, Webpack, Vite

Backend Kotlin, Spring Boot, Java, JUnit, Keycloak, Node, js, Python, Elasticsearch

Developer Tools Git, ConcourseCI, Kubernetes, GCP, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Grafana, Pormetheus, Docker

EXPERIENCE

Boclips, Tech Lead, Remote

Sept 2023 - Dec $2023 \cdot 3$ months

Working for a dynamic London startup in an XP team, which included pair programming on a daily basis. Kotlin, TypeScript, React, Kubernetes, GCP Elasticsearch, DDD, TDD, XP

- Collaborated with Product Managers and Engineering Leads to shape delivery plans for teams.
- Managed technical debt to ensure it was addressed in a sustainable manner.
- Ensured effective engineering practices were followed, including CI/CD, TDD, pairing, etc.

Boclips, Full Stack Engineer, London, UK/Remote

Nov 2018 - Sept $2023 \cdot 3$ years 9 months

- Built, designed, and maintained full-stack applications.
- Modernized tech stack, whilst migrating code and customers away from a legacy system.
- Improved web application load times using various techniques, such as caching and code splitting.
- Managed and mentored a junior engineer.
- Conducted initial technical interviews to hire engineers across all levels.
- Organised weekly "Lunch and Learn" sessions for the engineering team to promote knowledge sharing.
- Facilitated (including company-wide) retrospectives to evaluate and improve team processes.

Hawk-Eye Innovations, Software Engineer, Remote

Oct 2017 - Jun 2018 \cdot 9 months

Working in Hawk-Eye's SMARTData team, developed data-driven web technologies and real-time graphics engines in an agile environment.

- Optimised an HTML5 data-driven broadcast graphics engine for FIVB's Volleyball Nations League
- Enhanced an interactive timeline for use alongside Hawk-Eye's core replay software
- Played a significant role in sprint planning, backlog prioritization, and pull request reviews

Hawk-Eye Innovations, Junior Software Engineer, Basingstoke

Jun 2015 - Aug 2016 \cdot 1 year 3 months

I was a junior software developer working in Hawk-Eye's replay technology team, working on projects related to some of the world's top sporting events. Responsibilities included delivering new features and general bug fixing.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science, Bath University

2013-2017